## **Bouidia Abderrahmene**

## Software Engineer



## **PROFILE**

I am a computer engineer specialized in software development, I do mobile & web development (Front-end & Back-end) and I can also create desktop application. I love programming and I like spending my time on learning new programming languages and frameworks.

My goal in next five years is to be an expert in software development, after that maybe I will change the world.

# **CONTACT**



#### **Phone**

00 213 662 030 891



#### **Email**

abderrahmene\_bouidia@hotmail.com



#### **Address**

Door 35, Bloc 15, city 927 housing, Bir-el-djir Oran Algeria



#### LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/abderrahmene-bouidia



#### Web

abderrahmenedz.github.io/Portfolio/

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### Software Developer

june 2018 - until now

Software Developer at SPA Metidji Holding (one of the biggest company specialized in agri-food production in Algeria).

### Full Stack Web Developer

sept 2018 - until now

Development of Personal Project (Web Application: Soukna.app) using Angular 6 for the development of the front-end side and Asp. Net Web Api for the back-end side.

## **Android Developer**

ian 2018 - iun 2018

As a freelancer, I designed and created an Android application for a client. The app was developed with Java / Android SDK, It helps users of Oran city to locate different places like resterants, hotels, beaches of Oran city (west of Algeria).

### Software Developer

sept 2018 - iun 2018

At Deo Electronic (company specialized in CTM centralized technical management / Domotics), my role at this company was to design, to code, and to test and android application for domotic utilization.

### Software Developer

jun 2017 - jul 2018

In my free time, I created an Android Application using Java & Android SDK named Passwords Manager.

# **EDUCATION**

### Master Degree

2015 - 2017

A master's degree in computer science, specializing in computer science and networking in the University of Science and Technology of Oran Mohammed Boudiaf USTO-MB.

#### Certificat Cisco CCNA 1-2 R&S

<u> 2016 - 2017</u>

Level two in training course of CCNA CISCO Routing and Switching V5.0.

### Bachelor's degree

2012 - 2015

Bachelor's degree in Mathematics and Computer Science at the University of Science and Technology of Oran Mohammed Boudiaf USTO-MB

## Diploma JAVA-ANDROID

<u>2013</u>

Java & Android programming training at School ABOURA ASSISTANCE PRO.

# **SKILLS**

#### Language

Arabic (Native), French & English (read, written and spoken).

#### Languages & Frameworks:

Java, C#, Pascal, HTML, CSS, Java Script, Type Script, SQL, SQLite, Firebase, Google Maps, Java-Android, Xamarin-Forms-C#, ASP.NET MVC/Web API,C/C++ Photoshop, SAP, ABAP, Angular, Android Volley, Entity Framework, JSON, REST.